in this video we're going to look at
creating correcting entries in GP and
compare that to the experience of
creating reversing entries and
correcting dimensions in business
Central to begin let's go to GP and
navigate to the general journal window
to correct a posted journal entry I'll
select the correct button here there are
two options to select from to back out
the journal entry or back out and create
a correcting entry for our purposes
we'll select the first option to only
back out the journal entry next I can
select the original journal entry year
and find or type in the journal entry
number I need to
reverse once I find the journal entry
number I can select
okay now I can see that the system has
pulled in the accounts and amounts and
reversed the debits and credits now we
can go ahead and post the correcting
entry now let's look at how we can
reverse that same posted journal entry
in business Central first I'll select
the general ledger entries window that I
have pinned to my dashboard for easy
access once in the general ledger entry
window I can search for the journal
entry I want to
reverse now that I have found the
journal entry I will select to reverse
the
transaction you can see it's defaulted
in the journal entry information for me
and I will process the reverse
veral once the reverse is complete you
can see it as reverse the amounts posted
in the original journal
entry finally let's say you noticed a
journal entry was posted using incorrect
Dimensions you could reverse the
transaction or you can use the correct
Dimension
functionality to correct a dimension
value again I will search for the
journal entry I want to
correct here you can see that we have
posted the 500 Dimension value for this
entry instead of choosing to reverse the
transaction we'll select to correct the
dimension in the new dimension value
code I'll select the correct Dimension
value for the journal entry I could also
enter the description as to why the
change is being made now we will run the
change Dimension
process once complete we can refresh the
window and see that the correct
Dimension value is on the journal
entry reversing and correcting
Dimensions is a quick and simple process
in business
Central to learn more about business
Central see the following resources